Register of the Survey of Race Relations records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Minor Documents, 1907-1934 (Boxes 33-38)
  - Classified Japanese institutions, Seattle, Washington (Box-folder 36: 351)
    3 pages; Communities; Japanese; Seattle
  - "Interview with Walter Wong," by C. H. Burnett, 1924 August 25 (Box-folder 36: 352)
    3 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Chinese; Seattle
  - Letter to J. Merle Davis, 1923 November 13 (Box-folder 36: 353)
    1 page; Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - Letter to F. T. Duhring from B. S. Haworth, 1923 September 18 (Box-folder 36: 354)
    3 pages; Investigations; Japanese and Chinese; Northern California
  - Letter to H. J. Bard, 1923 April 3 (Box-folder 36: 355)
    5 pages; Investigations, Americanization, Race consciousness, Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - Letter to Professor C. E. Rugh from William Greenwell, principal, Lincoln School, Oakland, 1924 November 13 (Box-folder 36: 356)
    3 pages; Americanization; Chinese; Northern California
  - "Life History of a Maltese Immigrant," by Eleanor A. Tierney (Box-folder 36: 357)
    3 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Maltese; Dr. Park
  - "History of Rosalie Alioto Castelloni," by Bertha H. M. Monroe (Box-folder 36: 358)
    3 pages; Life histories; Italian, Dr. Park
  - Autobiography, Swiss immigrant (Box-folder 36: 359)
    4 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness, Life histories; Swiss; Dr. Park
  - "Biography, T. Matzimoto," San Diego, California, by Jeanette Wrottenberg (Box-folder 36: 360)
    2 pages; Goodwill, Life histories, Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Biography, T. Kumamoto," Los Angeles, California, by Jeanette Wrottenberg (Box-folder 36: 361)
    1 page; Communities, Life histories; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Biography, Shigira Kanamine," by Jeanette Wrottenberg (Box-folder 36: 362)
    1 page; Americanization, Life histories; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Biography, Toshiyo Kanamine," by Jeanette Wrottenberg (Box-folder 36: 363)
  - Autobiography of Leo Truttmann, San Francisco (Box-folder 36: 364)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Social disorganization; Swiss; Northern California
  - "Lists of Magazines for Women and the Corresponding Types to American Magazines," by Jessie Sato, University of Southern California (Box-folder 36: 365)
  - "Mexican Life History," by Emily B. Axtell (Box-folder 36: 366)
    2 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Mexican; Southern California
  - "Interview with Mrs. Suzuki,' matron, Japanese Y.W.C.A., Los Angeles, by Catharine Holt, 1924 December 9 (Box-folder 36: 367)
  - Letter to President R. L. Wilbur from a common laborer, 1925 March 27 (Box-folder 36: 368)
    2 pages; Competition and land; Mexican; Northern California
  - Jottings from the Columbian (Box-folder 36: 369)
    2 pages; Americanization, Competition and land; Japanese and Chinese; British Columbia
  - Chinese lotteries in San Jose, California (Box-folder 36: 370)
    5 pages; Social disorganization; Chinese; Northern California
  - Letter to Professor Eliot G. Mears regarding the number of British Indians in the three Pacific Coast states and in British Columbia, 1925 March 16 (Box-folder 36: 371)
    1 page; Population; East Indians; Northern California
  - "Will of Takazo Takatsuji as Translated by Ishie," submitted by C. D. Joy, El Centro, California (Box-folder 36: 372)
  - Letter to the editor, The Imperial Valley Press, submitted by C. D. Joy, El Centro, California (Box-folder 36: 373)
    2 pages; Race consciousness, Population; Filipino; Southern California
  - Classification of Oriental students by courses, University of California, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 36: 374)
    1 page; Population; Chinese, Japanese, and Filipino; Northern California
  - "Intermarriage of Mr. Suyetomi: Interview with H. Otsubo," Hollywood, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles (Box-folder 36: 375)
    1 page; Intermarriage; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Family Problems among Japanese in America: Interview with H. Otsubo," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles (Box-folder 36: 376)
    2 pages; Heritages, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Work on New Mission Is Started," Pasadena Evening Post, 1923 October 18 (Box-folder 36: 377)
  - Visits of American-born to Japan (Box-folder 36: 378)
    2 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Life History of a Japanese," by Anna L. White, Southern California (Box-folder 36: 379)
  - "Life History of Harry Kawano: A Japanese," by Eleanora Vossler (Box-folder 36: 380)
    11 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "My Autobiography," by Misao Shibayama, 1924 December 11 (Box-folder 36: 381)
    10 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Second Generation: Interview with Joe Hirai" by William C. Smith, Los Angeles (Box-folder 36: 382)
  - Dr. Gladys Shabovitch, County Health Officer, Los Angeles County, Los Angeles, California, by Chloe Holt, 1925 February 3 (Box-folder 36: 383)
    2 pages; Social disorganization; Japanese and Mexican; Southern California
  - "Life History of a Chinese," by Gladys M. Leonard, Los Angeles (Box-folder 36: 384)
    3 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Canada and the Orient," excerpts from The Canadian Magazine, 1922 November (Box-folder 36: 385)
    3 pages; Population, Competition and land; Chinese and Japanese; British Columbia
  - "The Japanese Standard of Living," by Velva Darling, under the direction of Eliot G. Mears (Box-folder 36: 386)
    8 pages; Competition and land, Americanization; Japanese; Northern California
  - The Japanese Relations Committee of California makes statement to the people of California in connection with the proposed initiative amending the Alien Land Law of 1913 (Box-folder 36: 387)
    3 pages; Goodwill, Population; Japanese; Northern California
  - "Can California Do Without Japanese?," released by the California Joint Immigration Committee (Box-folder 36: 388)
    2 pages; Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - Memorandum of recommendations of sub-committee appointed at the conference between Viscount Shibusawa and the Japanese Relations Committee (Box-folder 36: 389)
    5 pages; Goodwill, Population; Japanese; Northern California
  - "Congress and Japan," text of a letter concerning the attitude of Japan in connection with the action of Congress excluding as immigrants aliens who are ineligible for American citizenship, 1924 July 25 (Box-folder 36: 390)
    9 pages; Race consciousness, Goodwill; Japanese
  - "Immigration Laws Cannot Stop Them," released by California Joint Immigration Committee (Box-folder 36: 391)
    2 pages; Population; Japanese; Northern California
  - "Japan, Geneva and Congress," statement released by the California Joint Immigration Committee, 1924 October 20 (Box-folder 36: 392)
    5 pages; Investigations; Japanese
  - "Japan's Cure for Dual Citizenship," released by the California Joint Immigration Committee, San Francisco, California, 1924 November 17 (Box-folder 36: 393)
    3 pages; Investigations; Japanese
  - "Crops Improved Under Whites," released by the California Joint Immigration Committee, San Francisco, California, 1924 November 18 (Box-folder 36: 394)
  - "Tourist Brides from Japan," released by the California Joint Immigration Committee, San Francisco, California, 1924 November 18 (Box-folder 36: 395)
    2 pages; Population; Japanese
  - "An Appeal to the Japanese Vote," released by the California Joint Immigration Committee, San Francisco, California, 1924 November 12 (Box-folder 36: 396)
    2 pages; Competition and land; Japanese
  - Letter from V. S. McClatchy to Sidney L. Gulick, 1925 May 19 (Box-folder 36: 397)
    2 pages; Investigations; Japanese; Northern California
  - Letter from V. S. McClatchy to Eliot G. Mears, 1925 July 23 (Box-folder 36: 398)
  - Letter from Harry E. Hull, Commissioner General, United States. Department of Labor, to Eliot G. Mears regarding immigration, 1925 May-June (Box-folder 36: 399)
    2 pages; Investigations, Population; Japanese, Chinese, and Filipino; Washington, D.C.
  - Letter from F. M. Hudson, Secretary of the Produce Exchange, Los Angeles, to Eliot G. Mears, 1924 October 31 (Box-folder 36: 400)
    5 pages; Competition and land, Americanization; Japanese and Chinese; Southern California
  - "500 Chinese Students in City School," extract from the San Francisco Examiner, 1925 October 18 (Box-folder 36: 401)
    2 pages; Americanization; Chinese; Northern California
  - "Goto Attacks U.S. Stand on Colonization," extract from the San Francisco Chronicle, 1925 may 25 (Box-folder 36: 402)
    2 pages; Communities, Population; Japanese
  - "Japanese Colonists on Ohio Farm to Hire White Labor, Promoters Say," extracts from Columbus Dispatch, Columbus Citizen, and Ohio State Journal, concerning a projected Japanese colony in Ohio (Box-folder 36: 403)
    7 pages; Communities, Competition and land; Japanese; Ohio
  - "Story of Ling Joe of Tulare," by Reverend Benjamin Gould, First Congregational Church, Tulare, California, 1924 July 3 (Box-folder 36: 404)
    2 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Competition and land; Chinese; Northern California
  - "Case of Woman, Raj Kaur," by H. V. White, Stockton, California, 1924 July 17 (Box-folder 36: 405)
    2 pages; Social disorganization; East Indian; Northern California
  - Digital copy of Box 37
  - Letter from Richard R. Perkins, General Secretary, Young Men's Christian Association, San Francisco, to Vaughn MacCaughey, 1924 May 9 (Box-folder 37: 406)
    5 pages; Americanization, Communities, Goodwill; Japanese, Chinese, and Filipino; Northern California
  - "The Oriental and Property Values in San Jose: A Problem in City Planning and Expansion," report, Committee of San Jose Realty Board to questionnaire, 1924 October 17 (Box-folder 37: 407)
    6 pages; Communities, Competition and land; Japanese and Chinese; Northern California
  - Letter from Elbert E. Chandler, Occidental College, Los Angeles, California, to George Gleason, 1924 May 2 (Box-folder 37: 408)
    2 pages; Competition and land; Hindu; Southern California
  - Hearings before the Committee on Immigration, United States. Congress. Senate (S 2576), 1924 (Box-folder 37: 409)
    4 pages; Investigations: Legislation, Competition and land; Oriental/Asiatic
  - Statement relating to Oriental gambling in Northern California (source unknown) (Box-folder 37: 410)
    4 pages; Social disorganization; Japanese and Chinese; Northern California
  - The Japanese situation in Turlock County, California, during the Melon Harvest, 1921 July (Box-folder 37: 411)
    3 pages; Competition and land; Japanese; Northern California
  - Population and occupation of Filipinos and Chinese in San Joaquin County, California (Box-folder 37: 412)
    2 pages; Population; Chinese and Filipino; Northern California
  - Talk, Eliot G. Mears, questions asked regarding Orientals, First Congregational Church, Oakland, California, 1925 May 24 (Box-folder 37: 413)
  - "Asiatic Problem also Menaces Future of British Columbia," extract from Illustrated Daily News, Los Angeles, California, 1924 August 2 (Box-folder 37: 414)
    2 pages; Competition and land; Oriental/Asiatic; British Columbia
  - Study of vote cast in 1920 on Alien Land Law (Box-folder 37: 415)
    5 pages; Investigations; Orientals/Asiatic; Northern and Southern California
  - The Koreans in Southern California (Box-folder 37: 416)
    8 pages; Goodwill; Korean; Southern California
  - "The Place of the Korean in the Industrial Life of Los Angeles," by Adelaide Kim (a Korean girl) (Box-folder 37: 417)
    6 pages; Communities, Competition and land, Americanization; Korean; Southern California
  - "Life History of Chan Yue Wong," by Lorena Sperry, Southern California (Box-folder 37: 418)
    5 pages; Race consciousness; Chinese; Southern California
  - "The Younger Versus the Older Chinese in San Francisco," by Chan Yue Wong, Southern California (Box-folder 37: 419)
    8 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Japanese-American Intermarriage," by E. K., Southern California (Box-folder 37: 420)
    3 pages; Intermarriage; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Autobiography of a Japanese Student," by William C. Smith, Southern California (Box-folder 37: 421)
  - "Miss C," by Masao Dodo, Southern California (Box-folder 37: 422)
    6 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Life History of Kenichi Kawaguchi," Southern California (Box-folder 37: 423)
    18 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Story of Ung Soy Afook," by Curtis E. Avery, Southern California (Box-folder 37: 424)
    6 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Chinese; Southern California
  - "A Thumb Portrait of My Life History in Relation to America," by Magdaleno A. Abaya, Southern California (Box-folder 37: 425)
    9 pages; Life histories; Americanization; Filipino; Southern California
  - "Interview with June Goto," by William C. Smith, 1925 August 20 (Box-folder 37: 426)
    2 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Life history – Japanese, Los Angeles (Box-folder 37: 427)
  - Life history of Reverend Paul Tamura (Box-folder 37: 428)
    4 pages; Life histories, Goodwill; Japanese; Southern California
  - Autobiography of Shigeru Okada, Occidental College, Los Angeles, 1925 August 3 (Box-folder 37: 429)
  - "The Acculturation of Japanese Girls in California," by Shizuko Kawasaki (Box-folder 37: 430)
    9 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Life history of Shizuko Kawasaki, Southern California (Box-folder 37: 431)
    12 pages; Life histories; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Japanese Free Methodist Mission of Los Angeles," by Mr. Dodo (Box-folder 37: 432)
    3 pages; Goodwill; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Social Welfare Works of the Japanese M. E. Mission," Los Angeles, by Masao Dodo (Box-folder 37: 433)
  - Interview with Reverend Paul Tamura (Box-folder 37: 434)
    2 pages; Goodwill; Japanese; Southern California
  - Pasadena Buddhists: Interview with Reverend Paul K. Tamura (Box-folder 37: 435)
    1 page; Goodwill; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Japanese Churches in Los Angeles," by Marion Zook (Box-folder 37: 436)
  - "Los Angeles Japanese Reformed Church," Los Angeles, California, by Edna Vickstrom (Box-folder 37: 437)
  - "The Baptist, Chicago: Work Among the Hindus," by Theodore Fieldbrave, 1925 January 24 (Box-folder 37: 438)
    3 pages; Goodwill; Hindu
  - "Notes on the Japanese Community of San Diego," by Mollie Baker, San Diego (Box-folder 37: 439)
    14 pages; Community, Competition and land, Goodwill; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Life of the Japanese People in Montebello," by Llora Ashleigh, 1925 May 15 (Box-folder 37: 440)
    10 pages; Communities, Racial traits; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Mrs. K. S. Young," American-born Chinese woman, Los Angeles, California, by Catharine Holt, 1925 April 17 (Box-folder 37: 441)
    4 pages; Americanization; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Peter Soohoo (Chinese)," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1925 August 7 (Box-folder 37: 442)
    2 pages; Americanization; Chinese; Southern California
  - "The Life History of Edward L. C." (as written by himself), Southern California (Box-folder 37: 443)
    13 pages; Americanization; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Mr. Wong (Si Fu?)," Chinese merchant, Ferguson Alley, by Catharine Holt, 1924 July 29 (Box-folder 37: 444)
    1 page; Americanization; Chinese; Southern California
  - Digital copy of Box 38
  - "Young People's Week," 1925 April 5 to 11, report by Masao Dodo, Federation of the Japanese Young Men's Associations of Southern California (Box-folder 38: 445)
    23 pages; Americanization, Communities; Japanese; Southern California
  - Interviews regarding Melba Yonemura, mixed Japanese-American high school girl, Los Angeles, California, by Catharine Holt (Box-folder 38: 446)
    4 pages; Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Oriental Bits," by Marion Harrison, Southern California (Box-folder 38: 447)
    4 pages; Heritages, Intermarriage; Japanese and Chinese; Southern California
  - "Experiences with Orientals," by El Koempel, Southern California (Box-folder 38: 448)
    5 pages; Racial traits, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Receding Menace," Southern California (Box-folder 38: 449)
    3 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness; Chinese; Southern California
  - "My Knowledge of the Japanese and Filipinos," by M. Gardiner, Southern California (Box-folder 38: 450)
    4 pages; Americanization, Racial traits; Japanese and Filipino; Southern California
  - "Personal Experiences with the Orientals," by Curtis Smith, Southern California (Box-folder 38: 451)
    3 pages; Competition and land; Japanese and Chinese; Southern California
  - "Some Japanese Families in Southern California," by Constance Ricketts (Box-folder 38: 452)
    4 pages; Racial traits; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Oriental as I Have Known Him," by Kathryn E. Avery, Southern California (Box-folder 38: 453)
    3 pages; Americanization; Korean and Chinese; Southern California
  - "Relations with Orientals," by James N. Ewart, Southern California (Box-folder 38: 454)
  - "My Experiences with Orientals," by Fannie W. Boyd, Southern California (Box-folder 38: 455)
  - Letter to Professor Eliot G. Mears from George W. Hinman, 1925 May 8 (Box-folder 38: 456)
    San Francisco, California (5 pages; Goodwill; Japanese; Northern California
  - Letter to Eliot G. Mears from E. D. Merrill, Dean, College of Agriculture, California, 1925 March 18 (Box-folder 38: 457)
    2 pages; Competition and land, Americanization; Filipino; Northern California
  - "Problems of Second Generation," by F. K. Sakuda, Department of Sociology, University of Southern California (Box-folder 38: 458)
  - "My Life History," by L. Toyama (Box-folder 38: 459)
  - Personal letters received by Fumie Yanagisawa, age 13, after winning prize for best essay on "Patriotism" in American Legion contest, 1926 April-July (Box-folder 38: 460)
    5 pages